Guide to the Picture File, 1700s-1980s and undated RL.01025
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- People Series, 1700s-1970s; 1
  - Cary (Carey), Lucius, Second Viscount Falkland, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M680)
  - Catherine Parr, Sixth and Last Queen of Henry VIII, 1823 Aug. 1, engraving (Box 18, Folder M681)
  - Caton, Mrs. Richard (Polly Carroll), undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M682)
  - Catron, John, 1889, engraving (Box 18, Folder M683)
  - Cave, Edward, 1740, engraving (Box 18, Folder M684)
  - Cavendish, William, First Duke of Devonshire, 1835 Mar. 1, engraving (Box 18, Folder M685)
  - Cecil, Thomas, First Earl of Exeter and Second Baron Burghley, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M686)
  - Cecil, William, Baron Burghley, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M687)
  - Cenci, Beatrice, undated, card photograph (Box 18, Folder M688)
    Photograph of an engraving.
  - Cervantes Saavedra, de, Miguel, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M689)
  - Chaffin, Washington Sanford and Sarah A., 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 18, Folder M690)
  - Charles Edward Louis Philip Casimir, the Young Pretender, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M693)
  - Charles I, King of Great Britain and Ireland, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M691)
  - Charles I, King of Great Britain, undated, engraving (Box 51)
  - Charles II, King of Great Britain and Ireland, undated, 2 engravings (Box 18, Folder M692)
  - Charles II, King of Great Britain, undated, engraving (Box 51)
    Removed from M692.
  - Charles William Ferdinand, Duke of Brunswick-Lunenburg, and Augusta, Duchess..., 1791 Aug., engraving (Box 18, Folder M694)
  - Charlotte Augusta, Princess of Wales and Saxe -- Coburg, 1819 Aug. 1, engraving (Box 51)
  - Charlotte, Princess, 1829, engraving (Box 18, Folder M695)
  - Chartres, Duc de, Robert, 1800s, 3 clippings (Box 18, Folder M696)
  - Chase, Samuel, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M697)
  - Chaucer, Geoffrey, undated, 2 color photos (Box 18, Folder M697a)
    Two photo reproductions of painted portraits.
  - Cheatham, Benjamin Franklin, undated, 1 engraving and 1 page from scrapbook (Box 18, Folder M698)
    One of these engravings is from Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Chekhov, Anton Pavlovich, 1900s, handbill (Box 18, Folder M699)
  - Cherry, R. Gregg, 1949 Jan. 1, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 42)
    Includes personal note and signature of NC Gov. R. Gregg Cherry.
  - Chesnut, James, 1800s, card photograph (Box 18, Folder M700)
  - Christian, Prince, of Schleswig Holstein, undated, card photograph (Box 18, Folder M701)
  - Christian, W. J., 1884, card photograph (Box 18, Folder M702)
  - Churchill, John, First Duke of Marlborough, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M703)
  - Churchill, Sir Winston Leonard Spencer, circa 1940s, card photograph (Box 18, Folder M704)
  - Cibber or Cibert, Caius Gabriel (1630-1700), undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M705)
  - Claiborne, William C. C., undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M706)
  - Clark, C. E., 1916 Jan. 1, card photograph (Box 18, Folder M707)
  - Clark, Edgar Erastus, 1900s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 18, Folder M708)
  - Clark, James Beauchamp, 1900s, card photograph (Box 18, Folder M709)
  - Clarke, George Rogers, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M710)
  - Claude Lorrain (real name Claude Gelꥩ, undated, engraving (Box 18, Folder M711)
  - Clay, C. C. (Collection), 1864-1874, 86 card photographs (Box 19, Folder M712)
  - Clay, Green, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 19, Folder M713)
  - Clay, Henry, 1800s, lithograph (Box 51)
  - Clay, Henry, 1856-1873 and 1800s, 15 engravings (Box 19, Folder M714)
  - Clay, Joseph, undated, 1 engraving and 1 clipping (Box 19, Folder M715)
  - Cleburne, Patrick Ronayne, undated, engraving (Box 19, Folder M716)
    From Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1902, 1914 and 1900s, 5 black-and-white photographs (Box 19, Folder M717)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, undated, card photograph (Box 19, Folder M718)
    This photograph is published in "Mark Twain Himself: A Pictorial Biography" edited by Milton Meltzer.
  - Clementi, Muzio, 1833, engraving (Box 19, Folder M719)
  - Cleveland, Frances (Folsom), undated, card photograph (Box 19, Folder M720)
  - Cleveland, Grover, 1896 Nov. 28 and 1800s, 1 card photograph and 1 engraving (Box 19, Folder M721)
  - Cleveland, Stephen Grover, and his Cabinet, circa 1885, black-and-white photograph (Box 19, Folder M722)
  - Clingman, Thomas Lanier, 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 19, Folder M723)
    From C. C. Clay Papers.
  - Clinton, Sir Henry, undated, engraving (Box 51)
  - Clive, Robert, First Baron Clive, undated, engraving (Box 19, Folder M725)
  - Clopton, David, undated, card photograph (Box 19, Folder M726)
  - Clopton, John Bacon, 1800s, 3 card photographs (Box 19, Folder M727)
  - Clymer, George, 1888, engraving (Box 19, Folder M728)
  - Cobb, Howell, 1800s, 4 engravings and 1 card photograph (Box 19, Folder M729)
    All of these engravings are signed by Howell Cobb.
  - Cobb, Howell, 1800s, engraving (Box 42)
  - Cobb, Irwin Shrewsbury, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 19, Folder M730)
  - Cobb, Thomas Flourney, 1900s, 7 black-and-white photographs (Box 19, Folder M731)
  - Cobbett, William, undated, engraving (Box 19, Folder M732)
  - Cocke, Frances Allan (Ellis), 1884 Dec., card photograph (Box 19, Folder M733)
  - Cocke, John Field and Wife, 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 19, Folder M734)
  - Codrington, Sir Edward, 1830, engraving (Box 19, Folder M735)
  - Cogswell, Bela, 1800s, engraving (Box 19, Folder M736)
    Signed by Bela Cogswell.
  - Coke, Edward, undated, 2 engravings (Box 19, Folder M737)
  - Col. Robert H. Crockett (Davy), undated, black-and-white lithograph (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Colbert, Jean Baptiste, Marquis de Seignelay, undated, engraving (Box 19, Folder M738)
  - Cole, Thomas, portrait and three engravings of Cole's paintings, "Voyage of Life," 1800s, 4 black-and-white engravings (Box 58, Folder M1796)
    Portrait from Durand's original.
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1840, black-and-white lithograph (Box 59)
  - College girl in dorm room, circa 1920s, color illustration (Box 19, Folder M738a)
    Drawing by Farkas, with Coker pennant on wall.
  - Collier, Henry W., 1800s, card photograph (Box 19, Folder M739)
    From C. C. Clay Mss.
  - Collins, Wilkie, 1887 Feb. 5, engraving (Box 51)
  - Colquhoun, Sir Patrick Macchombaich, 1800s, engraving (Box 19, Folder M740)
  - Colquitt, Alfred H., 1800s, engraving (Box 19, Folder M741)
    Signed by Alfred Colquitt.
  - Columbus, Christopher, 1892, 2 black-and-white engravings (Oversize-folder 32)
  - Colvin, Lady Frances (Fetherstonhaugh) Sitwell, undated, card photograph (Box 19, Folder M742)
    Transferred from the Joseph Conrad Mss.
  - Colvin, Sir Sidney, 1900s, card photograph (Box 19, Folder M743)
    From the Joseph Conrad Mss.
  - Commander in Chief of the Grand Army of the Republic, 1885, color lithograph (Oversize-folder 44)
  - Compton, Spencer, Second Earl of Northampton, 1834 Nov. 1, engraving (Box 19, Folder M744)
  - Confederate and Union Commanders, 1884 and 1800s, 2 black-and-white photographic illustrations (Box 44)
  - Confederate Generals..., 1800s, 3 engravings and 1 black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 44)
    2 sheets of uncut trading cards printed by Chas. Magnus, 12 Frankfurt St., N.Y. 1 engraving. 1 photograph of a painting produced by Traveller's Insurance.
  - Confederate Generals..., 1862, 12 engravings (Box 19, Folder M745)
    Includes the original case for the first 24 engravings in this folder series.
  - Conrad, Joseph, 1924, postcard (Box 20, Folder M746)
    Etching by Walter Tittle; original in the National Portrait Gallery in London.
  - Considerant, Victor, undated, 2 engravings (Box 20, Folder M747)
  - Conwell, Russell Herman, undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 20, Folder M748)
  - Conyers, James H., 1896, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M749)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M750)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, et al, 1928 Aug. 19, 1 black-and-white photograph and 1 clipping (Box 20, Folder M751)
    The clipping is a photocopy.
  - Cooper, Anthony Ashley, 7th Earl of Shaftesbury, undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M752)
  - Cooper, Cropley Ashley, Earl of Shaftesbury, 1833, engraving (Box 20, Folder M753)
  - Cooper, James Fenimore, 1946, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M754)
    Photograph of a painting.
  - Cooper, Samuel, 1800s, engraving (Box 20, Folder M755)
  - Cooper, Sir Astley Paston, 1833, engraving (Box 20, Folder M756)
  - Copley, John Singleton, the younger, Baron Lyndhurst, 1830 and 1835, 2 engravings (Box 20, Folder M757)
  - Coram, Thomas, 1749 and 1808 Mar. 1, 3 engravings (Box 20, Folder M758)
  - Corby, William, circa 1899, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M759)
  - Cornwallis, Charles, First Marquis and Second Earl Cornwallis, undated, 4 engravings (Box 20, Folder M760)
  - Cornwallis, Most Noble Charles, 1796, color engraving (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Correggio, da, Antonio Allegri, undated, 2 engravings (Box 20, Folder M761)
  - Cortez or Cortes, Hernando or Hern⮬ undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M762)
  - Cotten, Robert R., undated, card photograph (Box 42)
  - Cotton Pickers, 1900s, 16 black-and-white photographs (Box 20, Folder M764)
    Photographs of African American laborers. Photographs were transferred from the Reuben Dean Bowen Mss.
  - Cotton, Sir Stapleton, Viscount Combermere, 1833, engraving (Box 20, Folder M763)
  - Courtenay, Edward, Earl of Devonshire (circa 1526-1556), undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M765)
  - Cowles, Calvin Josiah, 1800s, engraving (Box 44)
    Signed by Calvin Josiah Cowles.
  - Cowles, Ida Augusta (Holden), undated, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 20, Folder M766)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, chalk on paper (Box 55)
    Gift of Gay Wilson Allen.
  - Cowper, William, undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M767)
  - Cranmer, Thomas (1489-1556), undated, 3 engravings (Box 20, Folder M768)
  - Craven, William, Earl of Craven, undated, engraving (Box 52)
  - Crawford, George Washington, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 20, Folder M769)
  - Crawford, William H., 1800s, 3 engravings (Box 20, Folder M770)
    All of these include William H. Crawford's possibly authentic signature.
  - Creecy, Richard Benbury, undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 20, Folder M771)
  - Crittenden, John Jordan, 1863, engraving (Box 20, Folder M772)
  - Croker, John Wilson, 1832, engraving (Box 20, Folder M773)
  - Croker, John Wilson, undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M774)
  - Cromwell, Thomas, Earl of Essex (circa 1485-1540), 1823 Nov. 1, engraving (Box 20, Folder M775)
  - Crump, J. J., 1800s, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M776)
  - Cullom, Shelby Moore (?), 1800s, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M777)
    Transferred from Vause W. Marshall Papers.
  - Cunningham, Jr., George Alfred, 1900s, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M778)
  - Curran, John Philpot, undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M779)
  - Curtis, Charles, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M780)
  - Curtis, N. Martin, undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M781)
    Signed by N. Martin Curtis.
  - Cushman, Charlotte, undated, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M782)
    From C. C. Clay Family Papers.
  - D' Alembert, Jean le Rond, undated, engraving (Box 15, Folder M509)
  - da Vinci, Leonardo, 1800s, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1699)
  - Dahlgren, John A., 1800s, engraving (Box 20, Folder M783)
  - Dalrymple, Sir James, First Viscount Stair, undated, engraving (Box 20, Folder M784)
  - Daniel, John Warwick, undated, 1 card photograph and 1 black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 20, Folder M785)
  - Daniel, Peter V., 1800s, engraving (Box 20, Folder M786)
  - Daniels, Josephus and others, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M789)
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M787)
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1900s, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 20, Folder M790)
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1918, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 1)
    With handwritten note to Admiral Samuel McGowan, "with my affectionate regards."
  - Daniels, Josephus, circa 1940s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 52)
  - Dartmouth, William, Earl of, 1792 Mar. 3, engraving (Box 20, Folder M791)
    From the Georgia Histprical Society.
  - Daves, Edward Graham, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M792)
  - Davidson, Margaret (Miller), 1800s, engraving (Box 20, Folder M793)
  - Davie, William Richardson, 1800s, engraving (Box 20, Folder M794)
  - Davies, Henry R., Jr., 1800s, engraving (Box 20, Folder M795)
  - Davies, Samuel, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M796)
  - Davis, David, circa 1876, 4 card photographs (Box 20, Folder M797)
  - Davis, Jefferson -- Arriving in the Field..., circa 1861, lithograph (Box 42)
    Includes a note describing this image as an early Confederate imprint by Royler and Ludwig.
  - Davis, Jefferson (children...), circa 1867, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M799)
  - Davis, Jefferson, 1800s, 1 card photograph, 1 engraving (Box 52)
  - Davis, Jefferson, 1862, 1866 and 1800s, 6 engravings and 1 card photograph (Box 20, Folder M798)
    The last engraving has a negative available. The first engraving is from Charles E. Jones' Scrapbook. One of the engravings is from Edward A. Pollard's "The Lost Cause...," N.Y., E.B. Treat and Co., 1866.
  - Davis, Jefferson, 1868-1886 Apr. 28 and 1800s, 6 card photographs and 3 engravings (Box 20, Folder M798)
    One of the card photographs is from C. C. Clay Family Papers. One of the engravings is from Frank H. Alfriend's "The Life of Jefferson Davis," Cincinnati and Chicago, Carton Publishing House, 1868.
  - Davis, Jefferson, 1907 Sept. 6, 1866 and 1800s, 5 engravings, 1 postcard, and 1 card photograph (Box 20, Folder M798)
    The card photograph is from C. C. Clay Family Papers.
  - Davis, Jefferson, and Clay, Clement Claiborne, 1866, card photograph (Box 52)
  - Davis, Jefferson, and Davis, Varina (Howell), 1800s, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M800)
  - Davis, Jefferson, Jr., 1800s and undated, 2 card photographs (Box 20, Folder M801)
  - Davis, John William, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 52)
    Signed by John William Davis to James C. Hemphill.
  - Davis, Varina (Howell), 1899 and 1902, 1 card photograph and 1 clipping (Box 20, Folder M803)
  - Day, Jeremiah, 1847, engraving (Box 20, Folder M804)
  - De l'Epee, Charles Michel, Abbe 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M879)
  - De Soto, Hernando, undated, engraving (Box 52)
  - de Voltaire, Francois Marie Arouet, undated, postcard (Box 34, Folder M1700)
  - DeBow, James D. B., 1867 June, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M805)
    Photograph of an engraving from the June 1867 issue of "DeBow's Review." Negative available.
  - Decatur, Stephen, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 20, Folder M806)
  - Declaration of Independence, undated, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 1)
    Illustration of signing by John Trumball.
  - Deems, Charles M. Force, 1800s, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M807)
  - Deems, Charles Manning Force, 1878, lithograph (Box 20, Folder M808)
  - Delambre, Jean Baptiste Joseph, 1800s, engraving (Box 20, Folder M809)
  - Delany, Martin R., undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M810)
    Photograph of a sketch.
  - Delegates of the South and Southwestern Annual Conferences Assembled in Louisville, May 1845, black-and-white lithograph (Oversize-folder 36)
    Led to formation of Methodist Episcopal Church, South.
  - Denman, Thomas, First Baron Denman, 1820, engraving (Box 20, Folder M811)
  - Devereux, John, undated, 2 engraving (Box 20, Folder M812)
  - Devereux, Walter, First Earl of Essex..., 1824 Mar. 1, engraving (Box 20, Folder M813)
  - Dewey, George, 1915, card photograph (Box 42)
    Includes dedication and signature of George Dewey.
  - Dewey, George, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 20, Folder M814)
  - Dickens, Charles, 1800s, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M815)
    Transferred from the Chambers Band Papers.
  - Dickinson, Anna Elizabeth, 1800s, card photograph (Box 20, Folder M816)
  - Disraeli, Benjamin, First Earl of Beaconsfield, undated, engraving (Box 21, Folder M817)
  - Dix, John Adams, undated, 3 engravings (Box 21, Folder M818)
  - Dix, Roger Sherman, 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M819)
  - Doak, William Nuckles, circa 1930s, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M820)
  - Dobbin, James Cochrane, 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M821)
  - Doles, George, 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M822)
  - Dormer, Robert, Earl of Caernarvon, 1833 Apr. 1, engraving (Box 21, Folder M823)
  - Doub, Landon L., undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M824)
  - Doub, Peter, undated, lithograph (Box 52)
  - Doub, William Blake, 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M825)
    Photograph of a daguerrotype.
  - Doub, William Clark, circa 1870, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M826)
  - Douglas, Stephen A., 1862, engraving (Box 21, Folder M827)
  - Douglass, Frederick, Abraham Lincoln, and Booker T. Washington, with additional scenes, 1903, 2 black-and-white lithographs (Box 61)
    Conditions Governing Access
    2 items
    Poster title "Onward" of the three leaders, with small captioned scenes of boyhood homes and scenes, Tuskegee Institute, and others; copyright by W.L. Haskell. A second close copy adds lunettes of others such as Paul Dunbar, "Black Patti," W.E.B. Dubois, and others.
  - Dowd, William Bruce, 1880, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M828)
  - Dowell, G. J., 1800s, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M829)
  - Doyle, Sir Charles William, 1829, engraving (Box 21, Folder M830)
    Includes signature.
  - Drake, Sir Francis, 1829 Apr. 1 and undated, 2 engravings (Box 21, Folder M831)
  - Drayton, William Henry, 1872, engraving (Box 21, Folder M832)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 21, Folder M833)
  - Dryden, John (1631-1700), 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M834)
  - DuBose, D. M., 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M835)
  - Dudley, Lady Jane (Grey), 1825 Sept. 1, engraving (Box 21, Folder M836)
  - Dudley, Robert, Earl of Leicester, undated, engraving (Box 21, Folder M837)
  - Duignan, William H., circa 1840, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M838)
    From the George Jacob Holyoake Papers.
  - Duke Family Pictures, undated, 6 card photographs (Box 21, Folder M841)
    Received from "Four Acres." These unidentified images left in Picture File; 13 others removed to James B. Duke and Benjamin N. Duke Papers.
  - Duke, Brodie Leonidas, et al, circa 1912, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M840)
  - Duke, Brodie Leonidas, undated, 1 black-and-white photograph and 1 engraving (Box 21, Folder M839)
  - Duke, Washington, undated, engraving (Box 21, Folder M842)
  - Duke, Zebbean (Mrs.), 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M843)
  - Duncan, Adam, Viscount Duncan, 1831 and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 21, Folder M844)
  - Dundas, Henry, First Viscount Melville, 1831, engraving (Box 52)
  - Dundas, Robert Saunders, Second Viscount Melville, 1840, engraving (Box 21, Folder M845)
  - Dupont, Samuel Francis, 1800s, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M846)
  - Dupont, Samuel Francis, 1800s, engraving (Box 52)
  - Duranty, Walter, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M847)
  - Durell, Edward Henry, undated, engraving (Box 21, Folder M848)
  - Durham High School, class of 1905, 1905, card photograph (Box 42)
  - Durham, Bartlett, 1800s, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M849)
    Transferred from the Wm. K. Boyd Mss. Negative available.
  - Dyer, George Leland, 1909 Jan. 1, card photograph (Box 52)
    Signed to James Hemphill from Dyer.
  - Early, Jubal Anderson, 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M850)
  - Early, Jubal Anderson, 1800s, engraving (Box 52)
    Signed by Jubal Anderson Early.
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1961, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M851)
  - Echols, Joseph, 1800s, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M852)
  - Echols, W. H., Sr., 1800s, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M853)
    From the Albert Aylor Manuscripts.
  - Edward VI, King of England, 1833 Sept. 1, engraving (Box 52)
  - Edward VII as Prince of Wales, with wife and child, undated, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M854)
  - Egerton, Francis, Third and Last Duke of Bridgewater, 1833, engraving (Box 21, Folder M855)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1935, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 21, Folder M856)
    Negative available. Two of these photographs are duplicates.
  - Einstein, Albert: "To Albert Einstein, relativity and quanta are clues...," 1950s?, color photographic clipping (Box 45)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David, 1950, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David, circa 1940s, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M857)
  - Elbert, Samuel, 1798, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M858)
    Photograph of an engraving. Includes explanatory letters from the Naval Historical Foundation.
  - Elena, Queen of Italy, undated, postcard (Box 21, Folder M859)
  - Elizabeth I, Queen of England and Ireland, undated, engraving (Box 21, Folder M861)
  - Elizabeth, Princess of Great Britain and Landgravine..., undated, engraving (Box 21, Folder M860)
  - Ellicott, Benjamin, 1822, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M862)
    Photograph of an oil painting. Transferred from the David E. Evans Papers.
  - Ellicott, Joseph, circa 1820, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M863)
    Photograph of a deguerrotype copy of an oil painting.
  - Elliott, Stephen, (1806-1866), 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 21, Folder M864)
    One engraving is from the Georgia Historical Society.
  - [Ellis, Charles and Margaret Keeling (Nimmo)], circa 1870 and 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 21, Folder M865)
  - Ellis, George James Welbore Agar, First Baron Dover, 1830, engraving (Box 21, Folder M866)
  - Ellis, Henry Welbore Agar, Viscount Clifden, 1830 and 1836, 2 engravings (Box 21, Folder M867)
  - Ellis, Richard S., Jr., 1800s, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M868)
  - Ellis, Thomas H., 1879 Mar. 17, card photograph (Box 21, Folder M869)
  - Ellsworth, Elmer Ephraim, 1862, engraving (Box 21, Folder M870)
    Attached note: "This happened in Alexandria at the Marshall House."
  - Ellsworth, Oliver, 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M871)
  - Elzey, Arnold, 1864 June 18, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M872)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 21, Folder M874)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 52)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1860, 1873, and 1800s, 3 card photographs (Box 21, Folder M873)
    Transferred from the Isabell Howard (Perkinson) Willaimson Papers.
  - Emmet, Thomas Addis, 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M876)
  - Emory, John, 1820, engraving (Box 21, Folder M877)
  - Eng and Chang - Siamese Twins, 1839, lithograph (Box 42)
  - Engelmann, Gerson S., 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M878)
  - Erasmus, Desiderius, 1800s, engraving (Box 21, Folder M880)
  - Ernest Augustus, Duke of Cumberland and King of Hanover, 1832, engraving (Box 21, Folder M881)
  - Erskine, Thomas, First Baron Erskine (1750-1823), undated, engraving (Box 21, Folder M882)
  - Erwin, J. Harper, undated, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Estaing, Charles Hector, Comte D', undated, 3 engravings and 1 lithograph (Box 21, Folder M883)
  - Everett, Edward, undated, 2 engravings (Box 21, Folder M884)
    Larger image from Georgia Historical Society.
  - Everett, Reuben Oscar, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 21, Folder M885)